ayushveda.com 2011-12-08

# Privacy Policy | Ayushveda.com

We, at Ayushveda.com, take your privacy very seriously and abide by the following policy to ensure your satisfaction. If you have any concerns, please do not hesitate to write to us.  
  
  * What information does Ayushveda.com collect/track about me?
  * What does Ayushveda.com do with the information it collects/tracks? 
  * With whom does Ayushveda.com share the information it collects/tracks? 
  * Tell me about links with other sites.
  * Tell me about Cookies.
  * Tell me about Ayushveda.com’s policy on correcting, updating or removing personal information.
  * Changes in Ayushveda.com’s privacy policy.
  * Tell me about security of my personal information.
  * Tell me about e-mail choice/opt-out policy.
  * Tell me how to contact Ayushveda.com.

 **What information does Ayushveda.com collect/track about me?**

Ayushveda’s sole purpose is to promote the knowledge of Ayurveda world. Any doctor can apply for iayurveda service to get a free webpage, submit his/her articles and particiapte in Free Consultation.

The public (visitors, other members, or anyone not employed by Ayushveda.com) cannot use the information we gather to identify specific individuals.

Visitors to our site may browse, search and view articles or features without entering any personal information.

Ayushveda.com gathers two types of information. Information members submit to us and information not directly submitted by members.

  *  **Information members submit to us.**
    *  **Public:** We define public information (gender, age and height) as personal information that will be displayed on Ayushveda.com but cannot be used to identify a particular member. The personal information we gather may or may not include: customer-specified Ayushveda.com username, gender, age, religion, income range, occupation, preference/lifestyle information and general geographic location.
    *  **Private:** We define private information as information that allows others to contact a member through means other than Ayushveda.com. It includes information about the member other than what is displayed on the site.This information is gathered from members and guests who apply for the various services Ayushveda.com offers. This information includes, but is not limited to: email address, first name, last name, , a user-specified password, mailing address, zip code and telephone number.
    *  **Surveys & Contests:**From time-to-time Ayushveda.com requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age, etc.).
    *  **Ayushveda.com’s Partners:** The Partners program is a vehicle for other sites to link to the Ayushveda.com site. No personal member information is exchanged with Ayushveda partners.
  *  **Information not directly submitted by members to Ayushveda.com**
    *  **Aggregate:** This information — browser type and IP address — is general in nature and is gathered for all users of Ayushveda.com. It cannot be and is not used to identify any individual user.

 **What does Ayushveda.com do with the information it collects/tracks?**

Ayushveda.com uses the information it collects in the following ways.

  *  **Information members submit to us.**
    *  **Public:** Public information supplied by the member is intended to be viewed by visitors to the site. This information is used by visitors for searching purposes. Public information cannot be used to identify a specific member by name, address, etc.
    *  **Private:** We primarily use email addresses submitted by members to verify enrollment and when forwarding anonymous e-mails from ad responders. Respondees’ email addresses are not disclosed to the responder. We also use members email addresses to send news/updates regarding our site, but the member may choose not to receive emails of this type by unsubscribing.Email addresses may also be used in private correspondence with members for customer service. All other private information submitted by members is confidential and will not be disclosed except as required by law or to protect members of Ayushveda.com. All private information can be updated or deleted by the member at any time.
    *  **Surveys & Contests:**Contact and other information collected for contests will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for monitoring or improving user-satisfaction.
    *  **Ayushveda.com’s Partners:** Information submitted by the Ayushveda partner is used for establishing and maintaining a business relationship. No personal or business information is shared outside the relationship between Ayushveda.com and the Ayushveda partner. Ayushveda partners cannot view or access private information about Ayushveda.com members.
  *  **Information not directly submitted by members to Ayushveda.com**
    *  **Aggregate:** This information — browser type and IP address — is general in nature and is gathered for all members of Ayushveda.com. It cannot be linked to any individual user.

 **With whom does Ayushveda.com share the information it collects/tracks?**

Except where you are expressly informed otherwise or as described immediately below.

We do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information unless required by law or for the protection of your membership.

If you register with Ayushveda.com through one of our co-branded versions, your registration and profile information may be shared with the co-branding partner solely for the purpose of fulfilling the services provided by the co-branded site and any related promotional offers.

We encourage you to review the privacy policy of the co-branded partner for questions about their use of your personally identifiable information and how you can modify or delete it.  
  
 **Tell me about links with other sites.**

Ayushveda.com does provide links to other sites but is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Ayushveda.com  
  
 **Tell me about Cookies.**

Ayushveda.com uses cookies to deliver various services and to keep track of your personal preferences. A cookie is a small text file that can be entered into the memory of your browser to help a site recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s ongoing access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that allows Internet services to make content improvements and conduct targeted advertising.

If you do not want information to be collected through cookies, use the browser’s function that allows a user to deny the cookie feature. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion.

Please note that the use of cookies is a necessary part of the Ayushveda.com technology and is necessary if you wish to access Ayushveda.com. If you disable the cookie feature on your browser or delete cookie files from your computer, you may not be able to access certain features/services on Ayushveda.com. Cookies may also be necessary to provide you with certain features like customized look and feel, customized information, etc.

Ayushveda.com uses cookies to provide its services, to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit different pages on our site, and for other purposes. We do not and will not use cookies to collect private information from any user!

Also, please note that cookies are used only to recollect information sent to your computer from Ayushveda.com. We cannot access any information not sent by Ayushveda.com.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.  
  
 **Tell me about Ayushveda.com’s policy on correcting, updating or removing personal information.**

Ayushveda.com gives users several options for modifying or removing their information from our database. Please visit the My Ayushveda page to modify/remove your information or contact us.  
  
 **Changes in Ayushveda.com’s privacy policy.**

If we change our privacy policy, we will prominently post a link to those changes on our homepage so that our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email.

Users will have a choice to allow/disallow Ayushveda.com the use of their information in this different manner, and we will then use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.  
  
 **Tell me about security of my personal information.**

Ayushveda.com takes every precaution to protect its users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, the information is protected both online and offline.

All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees (customer service representative) who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, please contact us.  
  
 **Tell me about e-mail choice/opt-out policy.**

Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the instructions contained in the email.  
  
 **Tell me how to contact Ayushveda.com.**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us.  
  
Top  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>
